

Mekkattukulam (H), Kanippayyur, Thrissur - Dist. Kerala – 680517 mkm.nixon@gmail.com +91 7559962660



Microsoft

PERSONAL INFORMATION

Nationality : Indian
Gender : Male
Marital Status : Married

EDUCATION

- SSLC 2005 (Thrissur, Kerala, India)
- Plus-Two 2007 (Thrissur, Kerala, India)

CERTIFICATIONS

- MCP
- CCNA
- MEA(R)N Stack Web Development Angular & React

SKILLS

Front End:

JavaScript, TypeScript, React, Redux, Redux-Toolkit, HTML5, CSS3, SASS

• Back End:

Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB, Mongoose

DevOps:

Git, GitHub, Heroku, Netlify, Redux Dev Tools

Technical:

Operating Systems: Windows Server 2008 R2, 2012, 2012 R2, 2016; Windows 10. Database: Microsoft SQL, MS Access. Information Technology, End-User Support, Software & Hardware Installation

• Editing:

Adobe Photoshop

LANGUAGES

- English
- Malayalam

PROFILE

Skilled and 10+ years of experience in Cisco Networking, WIFI Solution, Virtualization, Windows Server, Surveillance system, Microsoft Office, and Troubleshooting.

I am a **Full stack developer** with experience in building websites and web applications. I specialize and have experience working with React, Node, Express, MongoDB.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

System Administrator / UI-Frontend Developer at S DEVELOPER Thrissur, Kerala, India

August 2017 - November 2022

System Administrator (August 2017 - May 2021)

- Support LANs, WANs, network segments, Internet, and intranet systems.
- Desktop Support, Printer Support.
- Active Directory management (adding and configuring new Workstations and setting up user accounts to provide authorizations.
- CCTV installation and DVR configuration & monitoring.
- Bio Metric device maintenance.
- Preparing Presentation Drawings in AutoCAD.
- Design and deploy networks.
- Documentation of all IT related Systems.

<u>UI-Frontend Developer</u> (May 2021 – November 2022)

- Implemented and completed Single page applications.
- Research latest technologies and implementing to the application based on clients need.
- Develop the themes and plugins.
- Customize the themes and plugins.
- Manage the project development team.
- Team Support.
- Training the junior programmers.

PROJECTS

MERN

https://github.com/SD-Books/nixon-project-11-todo-list.git

React.js Single page application

https://github.com/SD-Books/nixon-project-23-shoes-store.git

https://github.com/SD-Books/-nixon-project-24-single-webpage.git

LINKEDIN

https://www.linkedin.com/in/nixon-varghese-developer/

Hardware and System Support Technician at AL HUWAILATH ELECRONICS EQUIP.

RAK, UAE

February 2016 – June 2017

- ELV systems installation and configuration (CCTV, Biometric, PABX, etc.)
- Support LAN's, WAN's, Network segments, Internet and Intranet systems.
- Active Directory management (adding and configuring new Workstations and setting up user accounts to provide authorizations.
- Preparing presentation drawing in AUTOCAD.

Information Technology Support Technician at CLICKOWNZ Malappuram, Kerala, India

August 2010 – December 2015

- Computer Assembling, Installing, and Trouble Shooting Systems.
- Active Directory, Firewall configurations, Backup configurations.
- Installing and configuring computer hardware, software, systems, networks, printers, and scanners.
- Documentation of all IT related systems.

System Administrator at AL SULTAN GENERAL TRADING EST. Abu Dhabi, UAE

July 2009 - May 2010

- Handling Company Management Software, Backend software support.
- Install Network and Computer system.
- Maintain, Repair and Upgrade the Operating system including Hardware and Software.
- Ensure security through access controls, backups and firewalls.
- Ensure the security of the Servers and Network infrastructure by implementing privacy, security and regulatory compliance.
- Develop required reports in response to management needs.

Network Engineer at MANAPPURAM FINANCE PVT.LTD Tamil Nadu, India

March 2008 - June 2009

Management and maintenance of the central and branch office networks.

- Configuration and troubleshooting of routers for WAN links.
- Remotely Monitor and Manage WAN connections.
- Routing protocols: RIP, IGRP and EIGRP, OSPF.